

# Shivam Goyal

# Al Researcher | Deep Learning Enthusiast | Flutter Dev

I'm a budding Data Scientist who tries to get insights about what's benificial for a business and what's not by simply applying machine learning & statistical analysis on the pre-analysis data. I do love to keep the design and development process closer together, creating experiences designed for users first, while also taking care of business and brand needs.

shivamgoyal1899@gmail.com

(+91) 90122 18994



shivamgoyal.tk

in linkedin.com/in/ShivamGoyal1899

## **EDUCATION**

# **B.E. Computer Engineering**

Thapar Institute of Engineering & Technology

2018 - Present 8.63 CGPA

# **Senior Secondary**

Divine Educational Institute

2017 93.80 %

## **PROJECTS**

#### Gesture Controlled Robotic Arm

• This project focuses on replicating your hand movements to the robotic arm through deep learning model and openCV. So, no extra sensors are required except a laptop with a working webcam.

#### CreditCard Fraud Detection System ☑

A Credit Card Fraud Detection System based on Machine Learning algorithms. It sorts out fraudulent transactions from genuine transactions.

#### Movie Recommendation Engine **Z**

• It's a Movie Recommender System that predicts which movies you should watch next on the basis of your liked/last watched movie.

#### Affekt [Emotion Recognition App]

• Using Microsoft's Emotion API, Affekt can detect the emotion of the people in an image or even in real time!

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# ML & Flutter Developer

#### Enappd

06/2019 - Present

Bengaluru

- Developed Flutter Apps based on ML Algorithms.
- Conducted Bootcamps on Python & Git.

Contact: Abhijeet Rathore - fb/rathoreabhijeet

# **DSC Lead**

Google Developer Student Club

06/2019 - Present

# **Digital Marketing Internship**

Inkpothub

02/2019 - Present

Patiala

Contact: Rishabh Sahani - fb/rishabh.sahni.3956

# Android TV [ADT-2] Development Team

Google Developers

01/2019 - Present

Contact: Loic Wei Yu Neng - loicweiyuneng@google.com

# **SKILLS**



# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

## picoCTF (2018)

Bagged Global Rank 1415 in picoCTF 2018 with a score of 6435 among 16143 teams worldwide.

#### Google HashCode (2019)

Bagged Global Rank 945 & All India Rank 33 in Google HashCode Online Qualification Round 2019 with a score of 680469 among 6671 teams worldwide.

# **ORGANIZATIONS**

#### ORION'19 - InterYear TechFest TIET

WebMaster, App Developer & Tech Team Member

#### IEI Thapar Students' Chapter

WebMaster & Tech Team Member

## MaRS TIFT

WebMaster & Tech Team Member

## Facebook Developer Circle

## GeeksForGeeks

Founder | TIET Student Chapter

# **MAJOR CERTIFICATES**

Mathematics for Machine Learning Specialization Imperial College London

Applied Data Science with Python Specialization University of Michigan

# Machine Learning

Stanford University

## **LANGUAGES**

English German

Full Professional Proficiency Limited Working Proficiency

Hindi Punjabi

Limited Working Proficiency

# **INTERESTS**

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Blogging Solo Travelling LAN Gaming

**Event Management** 

**Graphic Designing**